CARLA SCHERER

Data Analytics, Data Science & Al

São Paulo, BR +55 51 993267470 carlatscherer@gmail.com Linked-In: carla-scherer-a4793b93/ GitHub: carlascherer

WHO AM I

I have experience working with agile teams on Data Science & Al projects, developing and maintaining solutions for financial services to automate and scale business flows using Artificial Intelligence in the Cloud. I bring strong mathematical, analytical and programming skills, combined with curiosity, the ability to self-input, learn fast and adapt, which allows me to excel in different tasks and environments. I hold a Master's degree in Civil Engineering with a focus on mathematical modelling of structures (2016-2018). I am Google Cloud (2021) and Azure (2020) certified and I have been specializing in Data Science (2021-now) and ML Engineering (2022-now) fields. I am motivated by solving problems using logic and exact sciences and by understanding how things work and why they are as they are. I always try to push myself out of my comfort zone.



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Accenture / Software Engineering Analyst 10/2020-Now

- Development of NLP model to extract information from non-structured documents (text documents)
- Development/improvement of python scripts for text mining
- Model improvement based on tracking of metrics
- Development of virtual assistants for the finance sector
- Design and implementation of the conversation flows and NLP entities and intents
- Development of python micro service to manipulate data and integrate the bot with external APIs

RS Highways Company / CORSAN / Civil Engineer

07/2018-09/2020 - 02/2015-02/2016

- Coordination of engineering services
- Elaboration of analysis reports and budgets using VBA
- Automation of day-to-day engineering tasks

EDUCATION

UFRGS, MSc. Civil Eng. - Structures *Research area: Wind Engineering/Wind Energy*2016-2018

UFRGS, Civil Eng. | Electrical Eng. (Incomp.) 2009-2013 | 2007-2009

DIGITAL HOUSE, Data Science mar-2020 - sep-2021

Provider California Cont.

Progr. Lang./Libraries

- Python
- Pandas/Numpy
- Scikit-learn
- SQL
- JavaScript
- Flask
- MatplotLib

Tools

- GCP/Azure
- DialogFlow
- Watson KS
- GCP AutoML
- Power BI
- Git/GitHub
- Kubernetes
- Excel

Knowledge

- Math./Stats.
- NLP/NLU
- Cloud
- OCR/AI
- DevOps, CI/CD

Soft Skills

- Communication
- Colaboration
- Resilience
- Flexibility
- Creativity